Now, the next architectural consideration or decision that you need to make while building a
rag-based application is on the chunking strategy. So, first let's quickly discuss what is
data chunking. Chunking is the process of splitting the documents or content into manageable
text segments or chunks for efficient data retrieval. So, what it means is let's say you have
a PDF document which is 10 pages. So, what you will do is you'll break it down into one page each
then in the one page you break it into Paris and then maybe a few lines. So, you create these
smaller chunks and once you have the chunks then you pass it through the embedding model to create
text embeddings. Now, let's go and look at various chunking strategies and which chunking strategy
you should use for what kind of a use case. Now, let's take a example let's say we have this PDF document
which talks about Lionel Messi so he's born in Argentina and it gives whole bunch of details. Let's
say this is 5 page long. Now, the first option from the chunking strategy perspective we have is
no chunking. So, you don't do any chunking. You take this entire document of 10 pages long
and you just create one embedding from the entire document. So, what's the downside for no chunking?
The retrieval precision is work because it's a single chunk. So, what is a use case for no chunking?
If you have very small documents maybe half a page or so then you can then you don't need chunking
you can just create one vector embedding. Okay, now let's take a look at the second one which is
the fixed chunking or it's sometimes also called default chunking. So, here you define the chunk size.
So, let's say every 120 words. So, either you define based on words, maybe characters,
code and so on. Now, let's say this is the document here. So, now here you can see in this gray
color we have the first chunk. So, I'm not actually calculated 120 words but let's just assume
these are 120 words. Then the second chunk is going to be this one in the orange and similarly then
we have the third chunk. So, every 120 characters there will be a new chunk that will be created
and then it will be passed through the embedding model. Now, to prevent data loss there is also
most of the time going to be some form of overlap. So, you can see here I have shown some overlap
maybe let's say this is 120 words and then maybe 10 words we are doing in overlap. So, you will have
this as the first chunk size and then the second chunk size rather than starting from here will start
from here. So, third we have cementing chunk which is the most precise and this is based on meaning.
So, you don't randomly split based on number of characters but you look at the meaning of topic
and then create chunk sizes. So, now let's say we have this entire page. So, in this case what
is going to do is it's going to split based on the meaning. The first chunk is maybe on introduction
and greatness about Lionel Messi then the second one is focused on childhood and Barcelona.
So, it is more structured around the meaning and relevance. So, this is by for the most
precise and accurate but it needs a lot more processing. So, last one is the hierarchical
chunking. So, we have the parent child relation here think of a technical manual. So,
let's say you have a guide for fixing the wind turbine. So, maybe it talks about
hierarchally about each of the parts. So, maybe it talks about the motor and then there are some
details on how to fix the motor. Then the next section is on the wings and then it talks about the
wings. So, now from the exam perspective let's say what are the chunking strategies and decision points.
So, now the first one is no chunking. So, for no chunking the pros would be it is easiest to implement
there is going to be lower cost and the negative point here is that there is going to be very
low retrieval precision. So, what are the best use cases maybe you have tiny documents,
short FAQs. So, when to choose when you have smaller documents and precision is not so
critical. So, the next we have the fixed size chunking. So, it is more like a default.
So, it is easier to implement and it is a good cost quality balance. But, what is the negative
point? It just splits based on the fixed characters. So, it can split some of the topics midway.
So, some of the good use cases is as I said it is default for most drag applications. So,
let's say you have blogs, guides and so on. So, when to choose as I said it is the default for
most drag applications when you need a good balance between cost and quality. And when the accuracy
is not of the highest priority, then we have the hierarchical chunking. So, high precision for
structured and hierarchy documents. So, it is much more complex and there is going to be more
cost and what is the best use case? Let us say technical manuals which follow a very hierarchy
structure. So, when to choose when you have large structured documents and accuracy is important.
So, it is much more accurate than the fixed size chunking. And then finally, we have a semantic
chunking which has the highest retrieval accuracy. It gives the best answer quality based on the
user query. So, what are the cons? More complex and higher processing effort that means it is
going to be more costly. What are the best use cases? Customer support boards where answer
quality is important, medical, legal finance, documents, rank-based solutions where stakes are
high. So, why to choose semantic chunking? When answer quality is more important than the
cost and implementation complexity. So, now, if I can quickly show you through the console,
so, I have in the bamens and butt rock service. So, let me just click on knowledge base
and then let me just click on create and then knowledge base with vector store and you can give
the name here, but we will skip for now. So, let us just choose the data source type at Amazon S3
and then I can just click on next and if I just cut the node to scroll down. So, you can see
your chunking strategy. So, we have the default chunking, then we have fixed size chunking,
hierarchy of semantic and no chunking. So, those are all the options that Amazon
bedrock provides. Okay. So, that is pretty much it from this lecture. As in the next lecture,
Thank you.